很久很久以前 在一个遥远的星系…
《星球大战：最后的绝地武士》
第一秩序的统治
摧毁了共和国
最高领袖 斯诺克
开始部署他那残酷无情的军队
试图重新控制银河系
唯独莱娅·奥加纳舰长与她的抵抗军
奋起反抗这崛起的暴政
能确定的是绝地大师卢克·天行者
将会重燃这场战斗的希望之火
但是与此同时抵抗军的位置也暴露了
随着第一秩序逼近叛军基地
勇敢的英雄们仓促撤离…
我们的库存还没清空啊
We're not clear yet.
在C仓还有30组炮弹呢
There are still 30 pallets of cannon shells in C bunker.
弹药不要了 我们没时间了
Forget the munitions, there's no time.
让所有人登船
Just get everyone on the transports.
噢 不
Oh, no.
逮到他们了 他们正好要撤离
We've caught them in the middle of their evacuation.
最高领袖斯诺克有令
I have my orders from Supreme Leader Snoke himself.
要让他们丧命于此 永不超生
This is where we snuff out the Resistance once and for all.
通知肯纳迪上尉准备好无畏舰
Tell Captain Canady to prime his dreadnought.
给我烧了他们的基地
Incinerate their base,
摧毁他们的飞船 消灭他们的舰队
destroy their transports and obliterate their fleet.
舰长 抵抗军船只接近
General, Resistance ship approaching.
火炮和护盾处于战斗状态
Guns and shields in attack mode.
一艘轻型战机
A single light fighter.
乐观点 兄弟
Happy beeps here, buddy, come on.
我们可做过比这还疯的事呢
We've pulled crazier stunts than this.
我郑重声明 达默伦指挥官
Just for the record, Commander Dameron,
这次我站在机器人这边
I'm with the droid on this one.
感谢您的支持 舰长
Thank you for your support, General.
乐观点
Happy beeps.
听着
Attention.
我是共和国舰队指挥官 波·达默伦
This is Commander Poe Dameron of the Republic fleet,
我有紧急事项要与赫克斯舰长通话
I have an urgent communicate for General Hux.
接进来
Patch him through.
我是第一秩序 赫克斯舰长
This is General Hux of the First Order.
共和国已不复存在
The Republic is no more.
你的舰队只不过是一群叛军渣滓 战争罪犯
Your fleet are Rebel scum and war criminals.
告诉你珍贵的公主 我们没有谈判余地
Tell your precious princess there will be no terms,
我方不接受投降
there will be no surrender.
你好 我在找赫克斯舰长
Hi, I'm holding for General Hugs.
我就是赫克斯 你和你的朋友完蛋了
This is Hux. You and your friends are doomed.
你们这群杂碎很快就会从银河系中消失
We will wipe your filth from the galaxy.
好的 等你转接
Okay. I'll hold.
喂
Hello?
喂 我还在
Hello? Yup. I'm still here.
你听得见我吗
Can he hear me?
- 赫克斯 - 他听得见
- Hux? - He can.
姓赫的 瘦瘦高高的小白脸
With an "H." Skinny guy. Kinda pasty.
我听得见你 你听得见我吗
I can hear you. Can you hear me?
我不等了 如果你们找到他
Look, I can't hold forever. If you reach him,
就说莱娅公主有急事跟他说
tell him Leia has an urgent message for him…
我想他是在捉弄你 长官
I believe he's tooling with you, sir.
是跟他母亲有关的
…about his mother.
开火
Open fire!
BB-8 冲啊
BB-8, punch it!
他朝无畏舰开去了
He's going for the dreadnought.
哈
Ha!
他这是疯了
He's insane.
喔吼 真带劲
Woo-hoo! That's got a kick.
好了 开始处理防空炮
All right, taking out the cannons now.
泰丽 开始行动
Tallie, start your approach.
收到
Copy that.
肯纳迪上尉 你怎么不把那只小苍蝇打下来
Captain Canady, why aren't you blasting that puny ship?
这只小苍蝇太小了 而且也太近了
That puny ship is too small and at too close range.
我们五分钟之前就应该
We need to scramble our fighters.
出动我们的战机
five bloody minutes ago.
他永远都击不穿我的装甲
He'll never penetrate our armor.
他不是想击穿装甲
He's not trying to penetrate our armor.
他是想损坏我们的防空炮
He's clearing out our surface cannons.
最后一炮
One cannon left.
大部队来咯
And here comes the parade.
对 对 我看到他了
Yeah! Yeah, I see him!
不 该死
No, no, no. Damn it!
BB-8 我的武器系统坏了
BB-8, my weapons systems are down.
我们必须把最后一门炮炸掉
We gotta take out that last cannon.
不然我们的轰炸机就完了
or our bombers are toast.
你快显显灵 兄弟
Work your magic, buddy.
自动火炮充能完毕了没
Are the auto-cannons primed?
准备就绪 长官
Primed and ready, sir.
那你还在等什么
What are we waiting for?
炸掉那个基地
Fire on the base!
冲啊
Punch it!
最后一艘船已升空 撤离行动完成
The last transport is in the air. The evacuation is complete.
波 你成功了
You did it, Poe.
现在 让你的中队撤回来 这样我们就可以离开了
Now get your squad back here so we can get out of this place.
不 舰长
No, General…
我们能办到的 我们有机会
We can do this. We have the chance.
干掉那艘无畏舰
to take out a dreadnought.
那些可是舰队杀手
These things are fleet killers.
我们不能就这么放任不管
We can't let it get away.
马上脱离战斗
Disengage now…
指挥官 这是命令
Commander. That is an or…
收起你那副紧张兮兮的表情 3PO
Wipe that nervous expression off your face, 3PO.
好的舰长 我尽力试试
Oh. Well, I will certainly try, General.
紧张兮兮
Nervous?
快啊 BB-8
Let's go, BB-8.
机不可失
It's now or never!
耶
Yes!
防空炮全部清除 轰炸机跟进
All clear! Bring the bombs.
上尉
Captain,
抵抗军轰炸机正在逼近
Resistance bombers approaching.
来吧
Of course they are.
轰炸机分队 保持紧凑队形
Bombers, keep that tight formation.
战斗机分队 全力保护轰炸机
Fighters, protect the bombers.
不是每天都能炸到无畏舰的
It's not every day we get a shot at a dreadnought,
大家把握机会
so let's make this count.
明白 蓝色领队
Copy that, Blue Leader.
你送我们到那 让他们尝尝厉害
You get us there, we'll give it to them.
- 收到 交给我们吧 - 敌机来袭
- Copy. We're on it. - Fighters incoming.
炮手 快
Gunners, look alive.
敌机 方位角210
Snubfighters at two-ten!
- 他们来了 - 保持队形
- They're coming in! - Form up!
他们到处都是
They're everywhere!
来了
Here they come.
敌机来袭 保持好队形
Incoming fighters. Form up.
加速到攻击速度
Vector in at attack speed.
- 拉升 - 包抄右侧
- Pull up! - Flank right.
呼救 我们正在下坠
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday! We're going down!
重新充能自动火炮
Recharge the auto-cannons.
对准那艘巡洋舰
Target their cruiser.
我看到了 泰丽 他们正瞄准我们的舰队
I see it. Tallie, they've targeted the fleet.
主炮已经进入充能阶段
and begun the priming sequence.
收到
Copy that.
我们就快到了
We're almost there.
投弹手 准备投放
Bombardiers, begin your drop sequence.
我已看到目标
I've got a visual on the target.
正在接近最佳点
We're approaching the sweet spot.
炸弹已激活
Bombs are armed.
- 自动火炮已瞄准 - 40秒后完成充能
- Auto-cannons aimed. - Forty seconds to full charge.
把最后一艘轰炸机干掉
Destroy that last bomber!
佩奇 回话 我们已经错过投弹点了
Paige, come in. We're over the target.
为什么你的投弹舱还没有打开
Why aren't your bay doors open?
你是最后一艘轰炸机了 全靠你了
You're the only bomber left. It's all down to you!
- 尼克斯 - 佩奇
- Nix! - Paige!
快投弹 快
Drop the payload now!
小心
Look out!
不
No!
炸弹已投放
Bombs away!
正中目标 无畏舰已摧毁
Direct hit! Dreadnought down!
舰长 最高领袖斯诺克
General, Supreme Leader Snoke.
从母舰打来找你
is making contact from his ship.
非常好
Excellent.
接到我的房间来
I'll take it in my chambers.
赫克斯舰长
General Hux.
啊 你好 最高领
Ah, good. Supreme Lea…
我对你的表现
My disappointment.
非常失望
in your performance cannot be overstated.
他们是逃不掉的 最高领袖
They can't get away, Supreme Leader.
他们已经是瓮中之鳖了
We have them tied on the end of a string.
蕾伊
Rey!
好样的 波
Well done, pal.
芬恩穿着个漏水服 什么 你的芯片是不是烧了
"Finn naked leaking bag"? What? Did you fry a chip?
芬恩 芬恩 好兄弟
Finn! Finn, buddy.
看到你真高兴
It's so good to see you.
什么 我们先
What? Let's…
我们先去穿件衣服 来吧
We need to get you dressed. Come on.
你一定有成千上万的问题
You must have a thousand questions.
蕾伊在哪
Where's Rey?
天行者大师
Master Skywalker?
我是抵抗军的人
I'm from the Resistance.
你妹妹莱娅公主派我来的 我们需要你的帮助
Your sister Leia sent me. We need your help.
你好
Hello?
走开
Go away.
邱伊 你来这干什么
Chewie, what are you doing here?
他说你会跟我们回去的
He said you're coming back with us.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
说来话长 上千年隼再说
Long story. We'll tell you on the Falcon.
千年隼
Falcon?
等等
Wait.
汉在哪
Where's Han?
没错 拴着缰绳 干得好 赫克斯舰长
Tied on a string indeed, General Hux. Well done.
很快抵抗力量就会落回我们手中
The Resistance will soon be in our grasp.
非常感谢 最高领袖
Thank you, Supreme Leader.
你知道我为何让这个偏激的坏蛋
You wonder why I keep a rabid cur.
坐上这么高的位子吗
in such a place of power?
一个坏蛋的弱点 只要精心操控
A cur's weakness, properly manipulated,
便能成为一把利剑
can be a sharp tool.
你的伤怎么样了
How's your wound?
不值一提
It's nothing.
嗯
Hmm.
强大的凯洛·伦
The mighty Kylo Ren.
当我找到你的时候
When I found you,
我看到了所有大师心心念念的
I saw what all masters live to see.
强大而野性的力量
Raw, untamed power.
这力量的背后 却尤其特别
And beyond that, something truly special.
就是你血统的潜力
The potential of your bloodline.
一个新的维达
A new Vader.
但现在
Now I fear.
恐怕我错了
I was mistaken.
我将自己的全部奉献给了你
I've given everything I have to you.
给了黑暗面
To the dark side.
把那可笑的玩意摘了
Take that ridiculous thing off.
是的 没错
Yes, there it is.
你父亲的善还是占据着你的心
You have too much of your father's heart in you,
年轻的索洛
young Solo.
我杀了 汉·索洛
I killed Han Solo.
那个时候 我根本没有犹豫
When the moment came, I didn't hesitate.
那现在看看你自己
And look at you,
这件事还让你魂不守舍的
the deed split your spirit to the bone.
你已经失衡了
You were unbalanced,
败给了一个连光剑都没摸过的女孩
bested by a girl who had never held a lightsaber!
输得一败涂地
You failed!
只要天行者还活着
Skywalker lives.
绝地武士的种子就还可能发芽
The seed of the Jedi Order lives.
一旦如此
And as long as it does,
银河系就会死灰复燃
hope lives in the galaxy.
我本以为你会掐灭这火花
I thought you would be the one to snuff it out.
看来 你不是维达
At least you're no Vader.
你只是个孩子
You're just a child.
只能躲在面具下
in a mask.
准备好我的船
Prepare my ship.
凯洛·伦心中已经没有光明了
There's no light left in Kylo Ren.
他只会日益强大
He's only getting stronger.
第一秩序会在数周内控制主要系统
The First Order will control all the major systems within weeks.
我们需要你
We need your help.
我们需要绝地武士回归
We need the Jedi Order back.
我们需要卢克·天行者
We need Luke Skywalker.
你们不需要卢克·天行者
You don't need Luke Skywalker.
你没有听到我刚说的话吗
Did you hear a word I just said?
你以为
You think what?
我会拿着一把激光剑跟你走
I'm gonna walk out with a.
然后只身对抗整个第一秩序吗
laser sword and face down the whole First Order?
你以为会怎样
What did you think was going to happen here?
你以为我是无缘无故
You think that I came.
跑到这个隐蔽的地方来的吗
to the most unfindable place in the galaxy for no reason at all?
你走吧
Go away.
不请到你 我是不会离开的
I'm not leaving without you!
小心
Careful!
你这是白费功夫
You're wasting your time.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
我知道这个地方
I know this place.
这地方是数万年前建的
Built a thousand generations ago.
为了保存这些
to keep these.
绝地典籍
The original Jedi texts.
就像我一样 这些都是最后的绝地信仰
Just like me, they're the last of the Jedi religion.
你说你见过这个地方
You've seen this place.
你见过这座岛
You've seen this island.
只在梦里见过
Only in dreams.
你是谁
Who are you?
抵抗军派我来的
The Resistance sent me.
他们派你来的
They sent you?
你有什么特别的吗
What's special about you?
- 你从哪来的 - 无名之地
- Where are you from? - Nowhere.
- 总有一个名字 - 贾库
- No one's from nowhere. - Jakku.
好吧 那的确是无名之地
All right, that is pretty much nowhere.
那你为何而来 来自无名之地的蕾伊
Why are you here, Rey, from nowhere?
抵抗军派我来的
The Resistance sent me.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
第一秩序已经势不可挡
The First Order's become unstoppable.
为什么是你来
Why are you here?
因为我内心一直存在某些东西
Something inside me has always been there.
现在它们醒了
But now it's awake.
我很害怕
And I'm afraid.
我不知道那是什么
I don't know what it is.
我不知道该怎么办
or what to do with it.
我需要帮助
And I need help.
你需要一个老师
You need a teacher.
但我教不了你
I can't teach you.
为什么不能
Why not?
我看你每天根本就不忙
I've seen your daily routine. You're not busy.
我不会再训练下一代绝地武士
I will never train another generation of Jedi.
我来这座岛就是为了等死的
I came to this island to die.
是时候 让绝地终结了
It's time for the Jedi to end.
为什么
Why?
莱娅满怀希望地派我来此
Leia sent me here with hope.
如果她错了 总得给她一个解释
If she was wrong, she deserves to know why.
也给我们一个解释
We all do.
- 你被降职了 - 什么 等等
- You're demoted. - What? Wait!
- 我们摧毁了一艘无畏舰 - 那代价是什么
- We took down a dreadnought. - At what cost?
你展开一场战斗 就应该战斗到底
You start an attack, you follow it through.
波 把你的脑子从驾驶舱拿出来
Poe, get your head out of your cockpit.
有些事情不是你跳进X翼战机
There are things that you cannot solve.
然后狂轰滥炸就能解决的
by jumping in an X-wing and blowing something up!
你必须明白这点
I need you to learn that.
这场任务里有很多英雄
There were heroes on that mission.
死去的英雄
Dead heroes.
死去的领袖
No leaders.
不知道这是哪儿
We're really nowhere.
蕾伊该如何找到我们
How's Rey gonna find us now?
隐蔽信标
A cloaked binary beacon.
照亮她的返家之路
To light her way home.
好吧 在她回来之前 我们的计划是什么
All right, so until she gets back, what's the plan?
我们需要找到一个新基地
We need to find a new base.
新基地必须能够提供充足电力
One with enough power.
便于发送救信号
to get a distress signal.
给分散在外环的盟友
to our allies scattered in the Outer Rim.
迫近警报
Proximity alert!
他们找到我们了
They found us.
这不可能
That's impossible.
那是斯诺克的飞船
That's Snoke's ship.
这是在和我开玩笑吗
You gotta be kidding me.
- 我们可以超空间跳跃吗 - 我们的燃料
- Can we jump to lightspeed? - We have enough.
只够跳一次
fuel resources for just one jump.
那就跳吧 我们必须离开这儿
Well, then, do it. We gotta get out of here.
等等
Wait.
他们通过光速轨道追踪上了我们
They've tracked us through lightspeed.
这不可能
That's impossible.
没错
Yes.
但是他们确实做到了
And they've done it.
所以如果我们超空间跳跃
So if we jump through lightspeed,
他们将再次找到我们 到时候燃料耗尽
they'll just find us again and we'll be out of fuel.
我们只有束手就擒了
They've got us.
不 还没到那种地步
Not yet, they don't.
请允许我驾驶X翼战机轰炸他们
Permission to jump in an X-wing and blow something up?
批准你的请求
Permission granted.
上将 迂回过去
Admiral, swing us around!
全速向后 旋转护盾
Full astern. Rotate shields!
各就各位 快 快
To your stations! Move, move, move!
听我指挥
Follow my lead.
绿色中队前往出发位置
Green Squadron to launch position.
清理发射轨道
Clear all launch traffic.
不用等我 跳上飞机后直接发动
Don't wait for me! Jump in and fire her up!
工作人员
Technicians,
限制补给 留待发射
lock down supplies for launch conditions.
快走 快走
Move! Move!
波 你还好吗
Poe, are you all right?
我们得撤到歼星射程之外
We need to get out of range of those Star Destroyers.
我们得怎么
We need to what?
引擎全速向前
Full engines ahead.
我们撤到歼星射程之外
Get out of range of the Star.
敌方就会撤回
Destroyers and the fighters will fall back.
全体船舰 全速前进
All craft, full engines!
将护盾集中在飞船尾部
Concentrate rear shields.
伦 抵抗军已经撤离到我们射程之外
Ren, the Resistance have pulled out of range.
这样的距离我们无法掩护你
We can't cover you at this distance.
快返回舰队
Return to the fleet.
如果连三艘小巡洋舰都没能歼灭
What is the point of all this.
那我们这次追击还有什么意义
if we can't blow up three tiny cruisers?
他们的飞船更轻 速度也更快 长官
Well, they're faster and lighter, sir.
他们甩不掉我们 但是也能和拉开一段距离
They can't lose us, but they can keep at a range.
让我们的炮塔无法击穿他们的护盾
where our cannons are ineffective against their shields.
继续轰炸
Well, keep up the barrage.
这至少可以提醒他们 我们仍然在追击
Let's at least remind them that we're still here.
是 长官
Very good, sir.
他们这样消耗燃料是撑不了多久的
They won't last long burning fuel like this.
摧毁他们只是时间的问题
It's just a matter of time.
快 别挡道 所有人 让开
Move! Out of the way, everybody! Give room!
生命体征微弱 但是她还有一口气
Life signs are weak, but she's fighting.
R2
Artoo?
Artoo!
对
Yes.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
嘿 这是座神圣的岛屿 说话注意点
Hey, sacred island, watch the language.
老朋友
Old friend.
我真想让你明白现在的情况
I wish I could make you understand.
我是不会回去的
But I'm not coming back.
什么都无法改变我的心意
Nothing can make me change my mind.
几年前 你在克隆人之战中效忠我的父亲
Years ago, you served my father in the Clone Wars.
现在他请求您帮助他对抗帝国的侵略
Now he begs you to help him in his struggle against the Empire.
很遗憾
I regret that I am unable to.
我无法亲自向您转达他的请求
present my father's request to you in person…
这招真是低级
That was a cheap move.
我的飞船遭受了攻击
…but my ship has fallen under attack,
恐怕无法带您回到奥德兰
and I'm afraid my mission to bring you to Alderaan has failed.
这是我们最危急的时刻
This is our most desperate hour.
请您帮帮我 欧比旺·克诺比
Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
你是我唯一的希望
You're my only hope.
明天天亮
Tomorrow at dawn.
三堂课
Three lessons.
我会教你绝地武士之道
I will teach you the ways of the Jedi.
还会告诉你为什么它该终结了
and why they need to end.
奥加纳舰长
General Organa,
莱娅
Leia,
仍然没有意识 但在逐渐恢复
is unconscious but recovering.
这是目前唯一的好消息
That's the only good news I have.
阿克巴上将 我们所有的领导人 都牺牲了
Admiral Ackbar, all our leadership, they're gone.
莱娅是战舰上唯一一位生还者
Leia was the sole survivor on the bridge.
噢 天哪
Oh, dear. Oh, dear!
如果她在这儿 她会告诉大家等战斗结束再难过
If she were here, she'd say save your sorrow for after the fight.
为了完成大业
To that end,
明显 应有人接替她的位置
the chain of command is clear as to who should take her place.
那就是宁卡号巡洋舰的
Vice Admiral Holdo.
霍尔朵中将
of the cruiser Ninka.
谢谢您 指挥官
Thank you, Commander.
我们三艘舰船上的
Four hundred of us.
四百人
on three ships.
是抵抗军仅存的成员
We're the very last of the Resistance.
但是我们并不孤单
But we're not alone.
在银河系的每个角落
In every corner of the galaxy,
被压迫的人们都知道我们的符号
the downtrodden and oppressed know our symbol,
他们将希望寄托于我们
and they put their hope in it.
我们就是那星星之火
We are the spark.
势必复兴共和国
that will light the fire that will restore the Republic.
这点星星之火 也就是我们抵抗军 必须存续下去
That spark, this Resistance, must survive.
这就是我们的使命
That is our mission.
现在 请回到你的岗位
Now, to your stations.
愿原力与我们同在
And may the Force be with us.
那位就是霍尔朵中将
That's Admiral Holdo?
指挥柴仑之战的霍尔朵
Battle of Chyron Belt Admiral Holdo?
跟我想象的的不一样
Not what I expected.
霍尔朵中将 我是指挥官达默伦
Vice Admiral? Commander Dameron.
以我们目前燃料的消耗
With our current fuel consumption,
避开歼星舰射程的
there's a very limited amount of time.
时间非常有限
that we can stay out of range of those Star Destroyers.
非常感谢你的提醒
Very kind of you to make me aware.
把燃料消耗情况汇报给我
Let's get me those fuel projections.
在找到新基地前 我们必须甩掉他们 所以
And we need to shake 'em before we can find a new base, so,
我们有什么计划
what's our plan?
计划 上尉
Our plan, captain?
你现在不是指挥官 对吧
Not commander, right?
莱娅的最后一道命令不是对你降级么
Wasn't it Leia's last official act to demote you.
因为你的无畏舰计划
for your dreadnought plan.
让我们损失了整支轰炸舰队
where we lost our entire bombing fleet?
上尉 指挥官
"Captain." "Commander."
你想叫我什么都可以
You can call me whatever you like.
我只是想知道现在的情况
I just wanna know what's going on.
你当然想知道
Of course you do.
我了解
I understand.
我对付过很多像你一样好战的飞行员
I've dealt with plenty of trigger-happy flyboys like you.
你意气用事
You're impulsive.
莽撞
Dangerous.
现在最忌讳这样行事
And the last thing we need right now.
所以你最好本分点 听从我的命令
So stick to your post and follow my orders.
七号和八号机组
Turbolink banks seven and eight.
正在维护 暂停使用
are offline due to maintenance.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
嗨
Hey. Hi.
呃 我只是在
Uh, I was… You know, I was just…
你是芬恩
You're Finn!
那个芬恩
The Finn!
- 那个芬恩 - 抱歉
- The Finn? - Sorry.
我整天都在和管道打交道
I work behind pipes all day.
不太擅长与你这样的英雄交谈
Doing talking with Resistance heroes is not my forte.
交
Doing…
交谈
Doing talking.
我叫罗丝
I'm Rose.
深呼吸
Breathe.
- 好 - 嗯
- Okay. - Yeah.
我不是抵抗军的英雄
Look, I'm not a Resistance hero,
与你聊天很高兴 罗丝
but it was nice talking to you, Rose.
愿原力与你同在
May the Force be with you.
哇 你也是
Wow. You, too.
好 不过你确实是一位英雄
Okay. But you are a hero.
你从第一秩序叛逃 还有在弑星者基地干的事
You left the First Order, what you did on the Starkiller Base…
当我们听到这些时 我妹妹佩奇说道
When we heard about it, my sister Paige said,
罗丝 那才是英雄
"Rose, that's a real hero."
明辨是非
"Know right from wrong"
即使每况愈下 他也不会逃跑
"And don't run away when it gets hard, " She said.
你知道
You know…
仅仅今天早上 我就打昏了三个人
Just this morning, I've had to stun.
因为他们想搭逃生舱逃走
three people trying to jump ship in this escape pod.
- 什么 - 他们要逃走
- What? - They were running away.
太丢脸了
That's disgraceful.
就是啊
I know.
不管怎么说 呃
Anyway, uh…
我得继续我刚刚没做完的事
Gotta get back to what I was doing, so…
你刚刚在做什么
What were you doing?
呃 只是
Uh, just…
- 做一些检查 - 检查逃生舱
- Doing some checks. - Checking the escape pods.
- 这只是例行检查 - 你所谓的检查
- No, it's routine checks. - By boarding one.
是带着行李登上逃生舱吧
with a packed bag.
好了
Okay.
听我说 我
Listen, I'm…
我动不了了
I can't move. I can't move.
- 我知道 - 发生了什么
- I know. - What happened?
我要送你去关禁闭 谁让你当逃兵
I'm taking you to the brig and turning you in for desertion.
我不是逃兵
I was not deserting.
- 我告诉你 - 我妹妹为了保护舰队
- I told you that… - My sister just died.
牺牲了
protecting the fleet.
而你却要逃跑
And you were running away.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
但是这支舰队注定难逃一劫
But this fleet is doomed,
如果我的朋友回来了 她也会丧生
and if my friend comes back to it, she's doomed, too.
我必须把这个
I've gotta get this…
我必须把这个信标带离这儿
I gotta get this beacon far away from here.
这样她找到我后 就能免于一死
Then she'll find me and be safe.
你这个自私的叛徒
You're a selfish traitor.
我们甩不掉第一秩序的舰队
Look, we can't outrun the First Order fleet.
我们可以超空间跳跃
We can jump to lightspeed!
他们可以通过光速轨道追踪到我们
Well, they can track us through lightspeed.
他们可以追踪到我们吗
They can track us through lightspeed?
是的
Yeah.
他们三十秒后就能追上我们
They'd just show up thirty seconds later.
而我们却耗掉了大量的燃料
and we'd have blown a ton of fuel,
更何况我们燃料严重不足
which, by the way, we're dangerously short on.
他们可以追踪到我们
They can track us through lightspeed.
没错 他们还可以
Yes. And they could…
我的舌头失去知觉了
I can't feel my teeth.
你用什么枪射我的
What did you shoot me with?
主动追踪器
Active tracking.
你说什么
What now?
超空间追踪是一项新技术
Hyperspace tracking is new tech.
它的原理与其它主动追踪器一样
but the principle must be the same as any active tracker.
- 他们就只能通过 - 只能通过
- They're only tracking us… - Only tracking us…
主舰追踪我们
…from the lead ship.
但是我们无法接近追踪器
But we can't get to the tracker.
这是一个A级程序 他们从主舰桥上控制它
It's an A-class process, they'll control it from the main bridge.
我知道 不过每个A级程序
Well, I mean, yes, but every A-class process…
都有一个专用的电源断路器
…has a dedicated power breaker.
但是 谁知道歼星舰的
But… Wait, but who knows where the breaker room.
配电室在哪
is on a Star Destroyer?
我以前经常在那晃悠
I'm the guy that used to mop it.
如果我们能到那里
If I can get us there,
我就能将他们的追踪器关掉
I can shut their tracker down.
再给我简单明了地解释一遍
Just give it to me one more time, simpler.
第一秩序
So, the First Order's only.
只能通过主歼星舰来追踪我们
tracking us from one Destroyer, the lead one.
所以我们去炸掉那艘战舰
So we blow that one up?
这个想法很好 但是这样行不通
I like where your head's at, but no.
他们还能用其他主舰追踪我们
They'd only start tracking us from another Destroyer.
但是如果我们能
But if we can…
如果我们能偷偷登上主舰 关闭追踪器
If we sneak on board the lead Destroyer and disable the tracker.
不知不觉地 我们就可以
without them realizing, then we can…
他们在一个系统周期内 是不会察觉到的
They won't realize it's off for one system cycle.
- 大约有六分钟的时间 - 偷偷登舰
- About six minutes. - Sneak on board.
关闭追踪器
Disable the tracker.
我们的舰队就可以悄悄逃离
Our fleet escapes before they realize.
嗯
Hmm.
你们两是怎么认识的
How'd you two meet?
碰巧遇见的
Just luck.
是吗
Yeah?
算好运吗
Good luck?
现在还不确定
Not sure yet.
波 我们必须这么做
Poe, we gotta do this.
这样既能救舰队也能救蕾伊
It'll save the fleet and it'll save Rey.
看来我要发出这里唯一的理性声音了
If I must be the sole voice of reason,
霍尔朵绝对不会同意这个计划
Admiral Holdo will never agree to this plan.
你说的对 3P0
Yeah, you're right, Threepio.
这是个「秘密计划」 不必向她请示
It's a "Need-to-know" Plan, and she doesn't.
- 我不是这个意思 - 好吧
- That wasn't exactly my… - All right,
你们俩去关闭追踪器
you guys shut down that tracker.
我在这儿准备超空间跳跃
I'll be here to jump us to lightspeed.
问题是
The question is,
如何偷偷登上斯诺克的歼星舰
how do we sneak the two of you onto Snoke's Destroyer?
我们可以去偷通行码
We steal clearance codes.
不行 那是生物密码 每小时更换一次
No, they're bio-hexacrypt and rescrambled every hour.
我们不可能悄无声息地通过安全护盾
We can't get through their security shields undetected.
没有人能办到
Nobody can.
我可以办到吗
Could I do it?
我当然可以 但我现在没办法帮你们
Of course I could do it. But I can't do it.
我现在脱不开身
I'm a little tied down right now.
噢
Oh!
玛兹 发生了什么事
Maz? What is happening?
联盟内讧 我说了你们也不想听
Union dispute. You do not want to hear about it.
不过 你们走运了
But, lucky for you,
正好有个我信任的人
there's exactly one guy I.
他能破解那种安全机制
trust who can crack that kind of security!
他是解码大师
He's a master codebreaker,
王牌飞行员 还是一个爆破高手
an ace pilot, a poet with a blaster.
天呐
Oh, my.
听起来这位解码兄弟无所不能
It sounds like this codebreaker fellow can do everything.
当然了
Oh, yes, he can.
你们去找他 这人西服翻领上有朵红花
You'll find him with a red plom bloom on his lapel.
正身处坎托湾赌场
rolling at a high stakes table.
在赌桌上豪赌呢
in the casino on Canto Bight.
坎托湾 不行 那是 玛兹
Canto Bight? No, no. That's… Maz…
有没有什么办法让我们自己解决这事
Is there any way that we can take care of this ourselves?
抱歉 孩子 这是非常罕见的破解法
Sorry, kiddo. This is rarefied cracking.
你想登上那艘星舰
You wanna get on that Destroyer,
我只知道这一种方法
I only know one option.
找到那个解码大师
Find the Master Codebreaker.
你会带我找到卢克·天行者的
You'll bring Luke Skywalker to me.
你这么做 会遭到反噬的
You're not doing this. The effort would kill you.
你能看到我周围的环境吗
Can you see my surroundings?
你会为你所做的一切付出代价的
You're gonna pay for what you did!
我看不到你的环境
I can't see yours.
只能看到你
Just you.
不对
So, no.
这其中有问题
This is something else.
卢克
Luke.
那是怎么回事
What's that about?
我在清理我的枪 不小心走火了
I was cleaning my blaster. It went off.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
那些东西是什么
Who were those things?
看护者
Caretakers.
岛上的原住民
Island natives.
绝地建筑建成后 他们就一直负责看守
They've kept up the Jedi structures since they were built.
我觉得他们不喜欢我
I don't think they like me.
我也想不到为什么
Can't imagine why.
天行者大师
Master Skywalker,
我们需要绝地武士回归
we need you to bring the Jedi back.
因为凯洛·伦体内有很强的黑暗原力
because Kylo Ren is strong with the dark side of the Force.
没有绝地武士的话 我们根本没有机会打败他
Without the Jedi, we won't stand a chance against him.
你对原力知道多少
What do you know about the Force?
那是绝对武士拥有的力量 可以控制别人
It's a power that Jedi have that lets them control people.
还可以让物体漂浮起来
and make things float.
厉害啊
Impressive.
不过你说的没有一句是对的
Every word in that sentence was wrong.
第一课 双腿盘坐在此
Lesson one, sit here, legs crossed.
原力不是你所拥有的一种力量
The Force is not a power you have.
和举起石头也没关系
It's not about lifting rocks.
而是万物之间的能量
It's the energy between all things,
一种张力 一种平衡
a tension, a balance,
能使宇宙万物凝结起来
that binds the universe together.
好吧
Okay.
它具体是什么
But what is it?
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
呼吸
Breathe.
现在
Now,
伸出来
reach out.
我感觉到了
I feel something.
- 你感觉到了 - 对 感觉到了
- You feel it? - Yes, I feel it.
- 那就是原力 - 真的吗
- That's the Force. - Really?
你的原力一定很强烈
Wow, it must be really strong with you.
我从来没有这样
I've never felt any…
嗷
Ow!
你说的伸出去是指
You meant reach out like…
我再试一下
I'll try again.
呼吸
Breathe.
只要呼吸就好
Just breathe.
跟着你的感觉延伸
Reach out with your feelings.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
岛
The island.
生命
Life.
死亡和腐烂
Death and decay,
孕育着新的生命
that feeds new life.
温暖
Warmth.
寒冷
Cold.
和平
Peace.
暴力
Violence.
那他们之间呢
And between it all?
平衡
Balance.
一股能量
An energy.
一种原力
A Force.
那你体内呢
And inside you?
我体内
Inside me.
也是一样的一种原力
that same Force.
这就是我要教你的
And this is the lesson.
这种原力不属于绝地武士
That Force does not belong to the Jedi.
如果说绝地武士消失 光明就没了 那是夸大其词
To say that if the Jedi die, the light dies, is vanity.
你能感觉到吗
Can you feel that?
这还有别的东西
There's something else.
在岛下面
beneath the island.
一个地方
A place.
一个黑暗的地方
A dark place.
平衡
Balance.
强有力的光明 强有力的黑暗
Powerful light, powerful darkness.
好冷
It's cold.
它在呼唤我
It's calling me.
反抗它 蕾伊
Resist it, Rey.
蕾伊
Rey?
Rey!
你直接走向了黑暗面
You went straight to the dark.
那个地方想给我看什么东西
That place was trying to show me something.
它展现你想要的东西
It offered something you needed.
而你却没有尝试阻止自己
And you didn't even try to stop yourself.
但我没看到你
But I didn't see you.
没有任何关于你的
Nothing from you.
你把自己和原力分隔开来
You've closed yourself off from the Force.
这也不奇怪了
Of course you have.
这种原始力量我之前只见过一次
I've seen this raw strength only once before,
就是本·索洛
in Ben Solo.
那时并不让我觉得害怕
It didn't scare me enough then.
现在却让我害怕了
It does now.
那是什么
What was that?
没什么 中将
Nothing, admiral.
只是些残骸
Passing debris.
剩下的燃料只够用18个小时了
The fleet's only got 18 hours of fuel left.
我们得抓紧了
We gotta hurry.
还是联系不上抵抗军吗
Still can't reach the Resistance?
继续联系
Keep at it.
如果联系上了 问问他们的情况
If you get through, check their status.
还有芬恩
And ask about Finn.
为什么原力会连结我们
Why is the Force connecting us?
你和我
You and I.
卑劣小人
Murderous snake.
太迟了 你输了 我找到天行者了
You're too late. You lost. I found Skywalker.
他告诉你发生了什么吗
Did he tell you what happened?
我烧毁圣殿的那天晚上 他告诉你原因了吗
The night I destroyed his temple, did he tell you why?
我所了解到的你已经够多了
I know everything I need to know about you.
是吗
You do?
噢 确实是
Ah, you do.
你的那种眼神
You have that look in your eyes.
和那时在树林里一样
From the forest.
你说我是个怪物
When you called me a monster.
你就是个怪物
You are a monster.
没错 我是
Yes, I am.
好了
Okay.
我们登陆 一找到解码大师就走
We get in, we find this codebreaker, we get out.
你了解坎托湾这个地方吗
You know this town? Canto Bight?
在书上看到过
From stories.
这里乌烟瘴气 窝藏着一帮银河系最坏的人
It's a terrible place filled with the worst people in the galaxy.
很好
Great.
我和那两个家伙说了
I told those two, I said,
这里是公共海滩 不能停穿梭机
"This is a public beach. You can't park that shuttle here."
但他们却熄了火 大步朝着赌场去了
But they just lit off toward the casino.
下注 下注
Place your bets. Place your bets.
现在下的注全部放到桌上
All bets on the table right now, right now!
把你的赌注放这儿
Place your bets here.
这个地方太赞了
Aw, yes! This place is great!
好了
Okay.
玛兹说这个解码大师的
Maz said this Master Codebreaker.
西装翻领上有朵红花
would have a red plom bloom on his lapel.
我们找到他 然后就走
Let's find him and get out of here.
很好 庄家获胜
Well played. The house wins.
你有没有素质啊
Where are your manners, more like?
快点
Come on!
整间赌场都找遍了
We've covered this whole casino.
没有戴红花的人
Zero red plom blooms.
这人到底在哪
Where is this guy?
该不会是那个吧
Were those what I think they were?
- 那些是什么玩意 - 法西骆
- What are those things? - Fathiers.
我从没亲眼见过
I've never seen a real one.
你看这个地方真漂亮 但是
Look, this whole place is beautiful. I mean, come on.
你为什么这么讨厌这里
Why do you hate it so much?
你再近点看
Look closer.
我和我妹妹在贫穷的采矿星系里长大
My sister and I grew up in a poor mining system.
第一秩序抢走了我们的矿石 来补给军队
The First Order stripped our ore to finance their military.
然后又用我们来测试武器
then shelled us to test their weapons.
他们夺走了我们的一切
They took everything we had.
你觉得这些人是干什么的
And who do you think these people are?
在银河系中只有一种生意
There's only one business.
能让人如此富有
in the galaxy that'll get you this rich.
战争
War.
把武器卖给第一秩序
Selling weapons to the First Order.
我真希望自己能一拳打倒
I wish I could put my fist.
这个污秽的又美丽的城市
through this whole lousy, beautiful town.
小红花
Red plom bloom!
解码大师
The Master Codebreaker!
对 就是他俩乱停机
Yep, those are the shuttle parkers.
好了
All right.
你们因违反禁停条例27B/6被捕
You two are under arrest for parking violation 27B/6.
你们有权保持
You have the right to remain…
- 那是什么 - 别说话 亲爱的
- What was that? - No, no, no. Not now, Lovey.
我手气正好呢
I'm on a roll.
第二课
Lesson two.
现在绝地武士几近灭绝 他们被神化了
Now that they're extinct, the Jedi are romanticized, deified.
但如果你揭开他们的神秘面纱 看到他们的所作所为
But if you strip away the myth and look at their deeds,
就能发现 他们的失败
the legacy of the Jedi is failure.
虚伪和狂妄自大
Hypocrisy, hubris.
那不是事实
That's not true.
他们的原力达到顶峰时 任由达斯·西迪厄斯
At the height of their powers, they allowed Darth Sidious to rise.
建立起帝国 消灭掉绝地武士
create the Empire, and wipe them out.
是绝地大师一手铸就了
It was a Jedi Master who was responsible.
达斯·维达这个错误
for the training and creation of Darth Vader.
也是绝地武士拯救了他
And a Jedi who saved him.
没错 他是整个银河系最痛恨的人
Yes, the most hated man in the galaxy.
但是你看到他内心的矛盾
But you saw there was conflict inside him.
你相信他还存有一丝善念 还可以迷途知返
You believed that he wasn't gone. That he could be turned.
然后我就成了一个传奇
And I became a legend.
这么多年 都保持着平衡
For many years, there was balance.
直到我看见
and then I saw.
本
Ben.
我的外甥 身上流淌着天行者的血液
My nephew with that mighty Skywalker blood.
然后狂妄自大的我
And in my hubris,
以为自己可以训练他 将我的力量传给他
I thought I could train him, I could pass on my strengths.
汉是汉 但是
Han was Han about it, but…
莱娅
Leia.
把他的儿子交给我
trusted me with her son.
我收他为徒
I took him,
还有十几个学生
and a dozen students,
建立了一座训练神殿
and began a training temple.
等我意识到
By the time I realized.
自己无法打败他内心滋生的黑暗时
I was no match for the darkness rising in him,
一切都太迟了
it was too late.
发生了什么
What happened?
我去和他对峙
I went to confront him.
然后他攻击了我
And he turned on me.
本 不
Ben, no!
他肯定以为我死了
He must have thought I was dead.
当我醒来时
When I came to,
神殿着火了
the temple was burning.
他带着我的几个学生消失了
He had vanished with a handful of my students.
而且残忍地屠杀了其他人
And slaughtered the rest.
莱娅觉得是斯诺克的错
Leia blamed Snoke,
但其实是我
but it was me.
我失败了
I failed.
因为我是卢克·天行者
Because I was Luke Skywalker.
绝地大师
Jedi Master.
一个传奇
A legend.
银河系也许需要一个传奇
The galaxy may need a legend.
我也需要有人来告诉我 要在其中扮演什么角色
I need someone to show me my place in all this.
你也没有辜负凯洛
And you didn't fail Kylo.
是凯洛让你失望了
Kylo failed you.
而我不会
I won't.
主舰仍然在射程外
The main cruiser's still keeping beyond range.
但他们的医疗护卫舰燃料已经用尽
But their medical frigate is out of fuel.
而且他们的护盾也倒了
and its shields are down.
他们的死期到了
The beginning of their end.
给我炸
Destroy it.
我们剩下的队员 已经朝你们的方向撤退了
The last of our crew has been evacuated and heading your way.
很荣幸为您效力 中将
It's been an honor, admiral.
天佑叛军
Godspeed, Rebels!
中将
Admiral,
燃料只能维持6个小时了
fuel reserves at six hours.
继续我们现在的航线
Maintain our current course.
稳步前进
Steady on.
芬恩
Finn,
罗丝 你们在哪
Rose, where are you guys?
加我一个
Deal me in.
谢谢
Thanks.
芬恩 星舰的燃料即将耗尽
Finn, the fleet is running on fumes.
没有解码大师帮我们登上敌舰
Without a codebreaker to break us onto Snoke's Star Destroyer…
- 我们该怎么办 - 我也不知道
- What do we do? - I don't know.
除非凭空变出个盗贼来 否则我们的计划就泡汤了
Unless you got a thief in your pocket, our plan is shot.
我可以
Um, I can do it.
什么
What?
抱歉
S-S-Sorry, I just.
我不是要故意偷听的
couldn't help but overhear all the stuff.
但是你们说得太大声了
that you were saying really loudly.
我正想要睡觉呢
while I was trying to sleep.
解码大师
Codebreaker?
盗贼
Thief?
我能做到
I can do it.
我们不是在说偷钱包 好吗
We're not talking about picking pockets, okay?
好吧
Yeah.
不要以貌取人 朋友
D-D-Don't let the wrapper fool you, friend.
我老早就和第一秩序的密码打交道了
Me and the First Order codeage go way back.
而且
And,
如果价钱合适
if the price is right,
我还能带你们 进老怪物斯诺克的卧室看看
I could break you into old man S-S-Snoke's boudoir.
- 不 - 我们 我们能处理
- No. - We're… We got it covered.
随便咯
Ha-tuk-ga.
- 他刚才是不是 - 是的
- Did he just… - Yeah.
我们得离开这里 这边
We gotta get out of here! This way!
为什么 你这个小
Why you little…
这是你做的
D-D-Did you do this?
嘿 举起手来
Hey, hands up!
- 举起手来 - 是的 长官
- Hands up! - Yeah, man.
你是什么来头 圆滚滚
What's your story, roundie?
他们去这边了
They went this way!
- 封锁所有出口 - 等等
- Lock down all the exits. - Wait.
闻起来真香
That smelled great.
警察随时都可能来 现在怎么办
Those cops will be here any minute. What now?
嗷
Whoa! Ooh!
不 等一下 请别按
No, wait. Please, don't!
我们是抵抗军
We're with the Resistance.
收到 立刻检查马厩
Roger that. Checking the stables now.
这边
This way.
他们肯定来过这里
They must have come through here.
驾
Hyah!
快走 快 快 呜
Go, go, go! Whoo!
别笑了 别笑了
Stop enjoying this! Stop enjoying this!
我们找到他们了 他们跑不掉的
We've got them. They're not going anywhere.
啊
Ahhh!
哈
Huh?
走开 走开 快让道
Move, move, move! Get out of the way!
我们的飞船在海滩上 往前直走
Our ship's on the beach straight ahead!
我们需要掩护
We need cover!
掩护太多了
Too much cover!
在那里
There it is!
快来
Come on!
别管兽群了 跟紧罪犯
Let the herd go. Stick with the perps.
他们去哪了
Where'd they go?
我们甩掉他了
I think we lost him!
我们现在去海滩 再绕一圈回来
Now we get down to the beach and circle back around…
悬崖
Cliff!
我们被困了
We're trapped.
值了
It was worth it, though.
我们把这里
To tear up that town,
搅得天翻地覆
make 'em hurt.
走吧
Go.
现在才值了
Now it's worth it.
他们在那
There they are.
BB-8 等一下 你居然会开飞船了
BB-8! Wait, are you flying that thing?
啊
Ah.
要搭顺风车吗
N-N-Need a lift?
卢克
Luke.
莱娅
Leia.
我现在不想见你
I'd rather not do this now.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
你为什么恨你的父亲
Why did you hate your father?
你能不能
Do you have something,
披上件斗篷什么
a cowl or something you could put on?
你为什么恨你的父亲 说实话
Why did you hate your father? Give me an honest answer.
你有一个爱你的父亲 他关心你
You had a father who loved you, he gave a damn about you.
- 我不恨他 - 那为什么
- I didn't hate him. - Then why?
为什么怎样
Why what?
为什么怎样 说啊
Why what? Say it.
你为什么
Why did you…
你为什么杀他
Why did you kill him?
我不明白
I don't understand.
你不明白
No?
你的父母把你当个垃圾扔了
Your parents threw you away like garbage.
- 他们没有 - 他们就是
- They didn't! - They did.
但是你仍然需要他们
But you can't stop needing them.
这是你最大的弱点
It's your greatest weakness.
四处寻找他们的影子
Looking for them everywhere,
以前是汉·索洛
in Han Solo,
现在是天行者
now in Skywalker.
他告诉你那个晚上发什么了吗
Did he tell you what happened that night?
是的
Yes.
不 他没有
No.
他感受到了我的原力
He had sensed my power,
就像他感受到了你的
as he senses yours.
他害怕这种力量
And he feared it.
骗子
Liar.
让过去安息吧
Let the past die.
必要时 就杀掉它
Kill it if you have to.
这样你才能完成自己的使命
That's the only way to become what you were meant to be.
不要
No! No!
蕾伊
Rey?
我应该感受到困惑或恐慌
I should have felt trapped or panicked.
但是我没有
But I didn't.
这不会永远持续下去
This didn't go on forever,
我知道它会指向一个地方
I knew it was leading somewhere.
最终 它会让我看到心中所想
And that, at the end, it would show me what I came to see.
蕾伊
Rey.
让我看到他们
Let me see them.
我的父母
My parents,
求求你了
please.
我以为我会在这里找到答案
I thought I'd find answers here.
我错了
I was wrong.
我从未感到如此孤独
I'd never felt so alone.
你并不孤单
You're not alone.
你也是
Neither are you.
蕾伊
Rey?
现在还不晚
It isn't too late.
停下来
Stop!
那是真的吗 你想杀了他
Is it true? Did you try to murder him?
给我离开这里
Leave this island now!
停下
Stop.
Stop!
是你做的吗
Did you do it?
你铸就了凯洛·伦吗
Did you create Kylo Ren?
告诉我真相
Tell me the truth.
我看到了黑暗
I saw darkness.
我感受到他体内的黑暗
I'd sensed it building in him.
在他训练的时候看到的
I'd seen it in moments during his training.
但当我看得更深时
But then I looked inside,
却发现它已远远超出我的想象
and it was beyond what I ever imagined.
斯诺克已经扭曲了他的心
Snoke had already turned his heart.
他内心的黑暗会带来毁灭 伤痛 和死亡
He would bring destruction, and pain, and death,
摧毁我爱的一切
and the end of everything I love because of what he will become.
就在那一瞬间 我出于本能
And for the briefest moment of pure instinct,
我以为我可以阻止这一切
I thought I could stop it.
然而这感觉转瞬而逝
It passed like a fleeting shadow.
只剩下羞愧
And I was left with shame,
和悔恨的后果
and with consequence.
我看到最后一幕是
And the last thing I saw.
一双充满惶恐的眼睛
were the eyes of a frightened boy.
被导师辜负的心灰意冷
whose master had failed him.
本 不
Ben, no!
你以为他误入歧途了
You failed him by thinking his choice was made.
但并非如此
It wasn't.
他内心仍在挣扎
There's still conflict in him.
如果他能弃暗从明 就能扭转整个局势
If he were turned from the dark side, that could shift the tide.
我们就能反败为胜
This could be how we win.
事情不会像你想的那样发展
This is not going to go the way you think.
它会的
It is.
就在我们双手相触的一刹那
Just now when we touched hands,
我看到了他的未来
I saw his future.
就像我能看到你的
As solid as I'm seeing you.
如果我去找他 本·索洛会改变阵营的
If I go to him, Ben Solo will turn.
蕾伊
Rey,
不要这么做
don't do this.
他会是我们最后的希望
Then he's our last hope.
尤达大师
Master Yoda.
年轻的天行者
Young Skywalker.
我会结束这一切
I'm ending all of this.
原力树 典籍还有绝地武士
The tree, the text, the Jedi.
我会烧毁这一切
I'm gonna burn it down.
哼
Hmm.
天行者
Ah, Skywalker.
我想你了
Missed you, have I.
所以是时候
So it is time.
让绝地武士团终结了
for the Jedi Order to end.
是时候了
Time it is.
嗯
Hmm.
该放下那堆旧书了
For you to look past a pile of old books, hmm?
那可是神圣的绝地典籍
The sacred Jedi texts.
你读过吗
Oh. Read them, have you?
- 我 - 令人爱不释手的书
- Well, I… - Page-turners.
才不是呢
they were not.
没错
Yes, yes, yes.
书中自有黄金屋
Wisdom they held,
但是那堆旧书里的东西
but that library contained nothing that the girl Rey.
蕾伊都具备了
does not already possess.
天行者
Skywalker,
你总是着眼于遥远的天边
still looking to the horizon.
从不考虑眼前
Never here, now, hmm?
你当下的需求
The need in front of your nose.
哼
Hmm?
我懦弱
I was weak.
愚蠢
Unwise.
你已经失去了本·索洛
Lost Ben Solo, you did.
决不能 再失去蕾伊了
Lose Rey, we must not.
我做不到她希望的那样
I can't be what she needs me to be.
你根本没听我说的话
Heeded my words not, did you?
把你的所学传于后世
Pass on what you have learned.
你的优点 精髓
Strength, mastery.
而不是软弱
But weakness,
或者愚蠢 和失败
folly, failure also.
是的 尤其是失败
Yes, failure most of all.
失败是最伟大的老师
The greatest teacher, failure is.
卢克
Luke,
他们日后会超越我们
we are what they grow beyond.
这是所有大师真正的责任
That is the true burden of all masters.
还有四秒差距 这真的发生了
Four parsecs to go. This thing really cooks.
我只是希望我们能及时到达
I just hope we're in time.
你可以做到的 是吗
You can actually do this, right?
关于这个
Yeah, about that…
朋友们 我可以做到
Guys, I can do it.
但是行动的前提 是要谈妥价格
But there exists a pre-"Do it" Conversation about price.
一旦任务完成 抵抗军会给你想要的
Once we're done, the Resistance will give you whatever you want.
你们有什么小金库吗
What you got deposit-wise?
我们看起来像暴发户吗
Are you kidding me? Look at us.
那是金月牙吗
Is that Haysian smelt?
这就差不多
That's something.
不 我们保证 你会得到应有的报酬
No, we gave you our word. You're gonna get paid.
你该知足了
That should be enough.
朋友们 我想要帮助你们
Guys, I wanna keep helping.
但你们可不能空手套白狼啊
But no something, n-n-no doing.
好吧 听着 你可以
Okay, listen here, you've got…
做事吧
Do it.
现在我可以继续帮忙了
Now I can help.
还回来
Give it back.
什么
What?
还回来
Give it back!
你根本不知道这块东西对她意味着什么
You have no idea how much that medallion means to her.
干什么 你还要洗劫自己的飞船吗
What are you… Why are you ransacking your own ship?
这不是你的飞船
It's not your ship.
他说是我偷的
He says I stole it.
- 我听得懂 - 是我们偷的
- Yeah, I got that. - We stole it.
至少你是从坏人手里偷来的
At least you're stealing from the bad guys.
这能帮助正义的一方
and helping the good.
好人 坏人
Good guys, bad guys,
不过文字游戏而已
made-up words.
看看谁是这艘豪华飞船的主人
Let's see who formerly owned this gorgeous hunk-uh.
啊 这人是个军火商
Ah, this guy was an arms dealer.
以售卖军火给坏人为生
Made his bank selling weapons to the bad guys.
噢
Oh…
也卖给好人
And the good.
芬恩 让我来告诉你
Finn, let me learn you something big.
那不过是个机器
It's all a machine, partner.
自由生活 不要加入
Live free, don't join.
那是他们最后的支援舰
That was the last of their support ships.
却成了现在的主舰
It's just their main cruiser now.
他们还有燃料储备吗
And their fuel reserve?
从计算来看
By our calculation,
捉襟见肘
critical.
她在吗
She in there?
舰长已经禁止你出入这里了
The admiral's banned you from the bridge.
- 不要胡闹 - 放心吧
- Let's not have a scene. - No, let's.
- 霍尔朵 - 你不能进来
- Holdo? - You're not allowed in here.
- 飞行员小子 - 够了
- Flyboy. - Cut it, lady.
我们以前有一个舰队 现在只剩一艘飞船了
We had a fleet, now we're down to one ship,
然而你却什么都不告诉我
and you've told us nothing!
告诉我 你已经有计划了
Tell us that we have a plan!
我们还有希望
That there's hope!
以前我在莱娅手下时
When I served under Leia,
她会说 希望就像一个太阳
she would say, hope is like the sun.
你只有相信它 才能看见
If you only believe in it when you can see it…
你撑不过今晚的
You'll never make it through the night.
是的
Yes.
你在给运输船加燃料吗
Are you fueling up the transports?
是了
You are.
所有的吗
All of them?
你要放弃主舰吗
We're abandoning ship? Is that…
这就是你想出的计划
That's what you got? That's what you brought us to?
懦夫
Coward!
那些运输船没有武器 没有护盾
Those transport ships are unarmed, unshielded.
放弃了这艘主舰 我们就完了
We abandon this cruiser, we're done.
我们丧失了机会 不 你不仅是个懦夫
We don't stand a chance. No, you are not just a coward,
你还是个叛徒
you are a traitor.
把这个人带出去
Get this man off my bridge.
芬恩 霍尔朵要让大家移到运输机
Finn, Holdo's loading the crew in the shuttle.
她要放弃主舰了 你在哪
She's going to abandon ship. Where are you?
波 我们在回舰队的路上
Poe, we're on our way back to the fleet.
快到了
We're so close.
你们找到那个解码大师了吗
Did you find the Master Codebreaker?
我们找到了 一个解码的人
Well, we found a codebreaker.
我们可以关闭追踪器
We can shut the tracker down.
再给我们点时间
Just buy us a little more time.
好吧 要快
All right. Hurry.
我一发射出去 你就往后 退出他们的射程
As soon as I launch, you jump back out of range.
然后等我给你集合点的信号
Stay there until you get my signal for where to rendezvous.
如果你在我之前看到芬恩
If you see Finn before I do,
就告诉他
tell him…
没错 就这么说
Yeah, perfect. Tell him that.
启动隐身装置 他们就侦查不到我们了
Cloaking our approach. We should be off their scopes.
然后切开他们的防线
Then we slice a slit in their shield.
哔啵 哔啵
Blip bloppity bloop,
滑翔进去
and slip right through.
你说突击队员和谁在干嘛
So a stormtrooper and a who now are doing what?
他们在努力拯救我们
They are trying to save us.
这是我们撤退的最好时机
This is our best chance for escape.
你一定要给芬恩和罗丝最大限度的时间
You have to give Finn and Rose all the time that you can.
你这是让抵抗军的幸存者
You have bet the survival of the Resistance.
命悬一线
on bad odds and put us all at risk.
没时间了
There's no time now.
我们必须要放弃主舰 运输机准备
We have to get clear of the cruiser. Load the transports.
收到 舰长
Right away, admiral.
好吧 我就知道你会这么说
Yeah, I was afraid you'd say that.
霍尔朵中将
Vice Admiral Holdo,
我现在解除你对
I am relieving you of your command.
全体人员以及抵抗军的指挥权
for the survival of this ship, its crew, and the Resistance.
你最好知道你在干什么
I hope you understand what you're doing.
当然
Yeah.
我会去那个连接通道
I'm going to the bridge.
如果他们有任何异动 打昏他们
If they move, stun them.
目前至少还要三周期
at least three cycles so far.
明白 长官 我们正在努力
Yes, sir. We are working on it.
我会尽我所能 长官
I will do my best, sir.
马上到了
Almost there.
你不必非要这么做
You don't have to do this.
我能感到你内心的挣扎
I feel the conflict in you.
它正将你撕碎
It's tearing you apart.
本 当我们双手相触时
Ben, when we touched hands,
我看到了你的未来
I saw your future.
尽管只有轮廓 但却准确而清晰
Just the shape of it, but solid and clear.
你不会屈服于斯诺克的
You will not bow before Snoke.
你会叛变
You'll turn.
我会帮助你
I'll help you.
我看的见
I saw it.
我也看到了些东西
I saw something, too.
因此我知道
Because of what I saw,
当那个时机来临时 你才是那个叛变的人
I know when the moment comes, you'll be the one to turn.
你会站到我这边
You'll stand with me.
蕾伊
Rey,
我看到了你的父母是谁
I saw who your parents are.
干得好 我优秀而忠心的好徒儿
Well done, my good and faithful apprentice.
我对你恢复信心了
My faith in you is restored.
小蕾伊
Young Rey.
欢迎
Welcome.
就是这儿
So this is it.
追踪器就在这扇门后面
The tracker's right behind this door.
金月牙
Haysian smelt.
最好的导体
Best conductor.
不用谢
And you're welcome.
是时候想想该怎么回舰队了
Good time to figure out how we get back to the fleet?
我知道最近的逃生舱在哪
I know where the nearest escape pods are.
你当然知道
Course you do.
BB-8 告诉我点好消息
BB-8, tell me something good.
波 我们马上就到了
Poe, we're almost there.
准备超空间跳跃
Have the cruiser prepped for lightspeed.
我正在做 你要快点
Yeah, I'm on it, pal. You just hurry.
清理连接通道 护送军官们去机库
Clear the bridge, escort the officers down to the hangar.
指挥官 达默伦上尉
Commander… Captain Dameron,
霍尔朵中将在找你
Admiral Holdo was looking for you.
我们谈过了
Yeah, we spoke.
长官 我恐怕要问一句
Sir, I am almost afraid to ask.
随心而动 去吧 3PO
Good instinct, Threepio. Go with that.
快关门
Seal that door!
我们快没时间了
We're running out of time.
快 怎么样了
Come on, how's it going?
就快好了
Almost there.
3PO 你要去哪里
Threepio, where do you think you're going?
参加兵变
It would be quite against my programming…
与我的程序设置冲突
to be party to a mutiny.
它不是正确的指令
It is not correct protocol.
噢 这也不是
Oh! Neither is this!
芬恩 我们已经准备好进行跳跃了
Finn? We're ready to make the jump!
机不可失
Now or never.
现在
Now.
你先去
You're up.
举起手来
You there, hands up!
控制他们 控制他们
Watch 'em, watch 'em.
立刻放下武器
Drop your weapons, now!
举起手 叛军渣滓
Hands up, Rebel scum.
趴下 我说趴下
Get down! I said, down!
FN-2187
Fn-2187.
很高兴看到你回来
So good to have you back.
他们失败了
They didn't make it.
莱娅
Leia.
请根据疏散指示
Please board the transports.
登上运输机
according to your evacuation designation.
清理所有的运输机
All transports must be cleared…
帮我把他推上去吧 各位
Okay, help me push him up, guys.
这人是个麻烦精
That one's a troublemaker.
我挺喜欢他的
I like him.
我也是
Me, too.
快来 该登上运输机了
Now, time to board your transport.
用于逃亡的运输机
For the transports to escape,
必须有人待在后方 驾驶巡洋舰
someone needs to stay behind and pilot the cruiser.
损失惨重啊
Too many losses.
我也再经不起失去了
I can't take any more.
你当然可以
Sure you can.
是你教会我的
You taught me how.
愿原力
May the Force be…
你继续吧 我已经说了太多次了
You go on. I've said it enough.
愿原力一直与你同在
May the Force be with you always.
隐蔽装置激活
Cloaking device activated.
我们要躲开他们的侦查
We should be off their scopes.
希望这个能有效
Let's hope this works.
孩子 过来点儿
Come closer, child.
你是如此富有力量
So much strength.
黑暗面一旦升起
Darkness rises,
光明面便如影随形
and light to meet it.
我警告过我年轻的徒弟 他变得越强
I warned my young apprentice that as he grew stronger,
他的光明面也就越大
his equal in the light would rise.
天行者
Skywalker…
恐怕
I assumed.
他错了
Wrongly.
我让你过来点
Closer, I said.
你低估了天行者
You underestimate Skywalker,
本·索洛
and Ben Solo,
还有我
and me.
你将会一败涂地
It will be your downfall.
噢
Oh…
你看到了什么吗
Have you seen something?
我徒弟的一个弱点
A weakness in my apprentice.
这就是你来此的原因吗
Is that why you came?
小傻瓜
Young fool.
是我连接了你们的思想
It was I who bridged your minds.
我激化了伦内心的矛盾
I stoked Ren's conflicted soul.
我知道他在你面前藏不住
I knew he was not strong enough to hide it from you.
而你 也还是愚蠢地上钩了
And you were not wise enough to resist the bait.
而现在
And now,
你会告诉我天行者的藏身处
you will give me Skywalker.
然后我会杀了你
Then I will kill you.
用最残忍的方式
with the cruelest stroke.
没门
No.
好
Yes.
把一切
Give me.
都给我
everything.
不 不
No! No!
不
No!
不 不
No. No.
不 不 不
No, no, no!
波
Poe.
那是什么
What is that?
矿物星球 克瑞特
The mineral planet, Crait.
地图中未标明的起义军隐匿处
An uncharted hideout from the days of the Rebellion.
- 那是个叛军基地吗 - 废弃的
- That's a Rebel base? - Abandoned,
但是那里
but heavily armored.
蕴藏着足够的能源
with enough power.
够让我们向分散在外环的盟友
to get a distress signal to our allies.
发送求救信号
scattered in the Outer Rim.
霍尔朵了解第一秩序
Holdo knew the First Order.
她在追踪我们的大型战舰
she was tracking our big ship.
他们不会监视小型运输机
They're not monitoring for little transports.
所以我们可以悄悄地滑到地面
So we could slip down to the surface unnoticed.
等第一秩序过去
and hide till the First Order passes.
这主意不错
That could work.
她在乎的是
She was more interested.
保护光明面
in protecting the light than she was.
而不是去当个英雄
seeming like a hero.
天佑
Godspeed,
叛军
Rebels.
干得好 法斯马
Well done, Phasma.
我们说好的 你的飞船和酬劳
Your ship and payment, as we agreed.
你这个骗子
You lying snake.
我们被抓了
We got caught,
我做了一笔交 交易
I cut a d-d-deal.
等等
Wait,
做了笔什么交易
cut a deal with what?
长官 我们核实这个小偷的情报
Sir, we checked on the information from the thief.
我们做了一次显现扫描 确信
We ran a decloaking scan, and sure enough,
30驾抵抗军运输机刚从机库起飞
30 Resistance transports have just launched from the cruiser.
他说的是事实
He told us the truth.
奇迹永远屹立不倒吗
Will wonders never cease?
非也
No.
我们的武器准备就绪了吗
Our weapons are ready?
已经瞄准 长官
Ready and aimed, sir.
随意扫射
Fire at will.
等等 不 不 你不能
Wait. No, no. No, you can't!
不
No!
舰长 我们受到攻击
Admiral, we're taking fire!
- 要掉头吗 - 不 你们离得太远了
- Do we turn around? - No, you're too far out.
向着坠落星球全速前进
Full speed to planetfall.
全速前进
Full speed!
好吧 好吧
Well, well,
我还没想到天行者这么有智慧
I did not expect Skywalker to be so wise.
我们会给他和绝地武士团
We will give him and the Jedi Order.
渴望的终结
the death he desires.
在判军消失之后
After the Rebels are gone,
我们会去他的星球
we will go to his planet.
摧毁那整片岛屿
and obliterate the entire island.
有勇无谋
Such spunk.
你看看
Look here now.
这些运输机上的所有抵抗军
The entire Resistance on those transports…
很快就会消失了
Soon they will all be gone.
因为你 一切成空
For you, all is lost.
不过 还有火热的希望
Ooh. And still that fiery spit of hope.
你有着真正的绝地武士精神
You have the spirit of a true Jedi!
正因如此
And because of that,
你必须得死
you must die.
我优秀的徒儿
My worthy apprentice,
黑暗面之子 维达大人的继承者
son of darkness, heir apparent to Lord Vader.
你的挣扎 变成决心
Where there was conflict, I now sense resolve.
你的弱点 变成力量
Where there was weakness, strength.
完成你的训练
Complete your training,
履行你的使命吧
and fulfill your destiny.
我清楚我的使命
I know what I have to do.
本
Ben.
你以为你能感化他
You think you can turn him?
可怜的孩子
Pathetic child.
我是不会被背叛的
I cannot be betrayed,
我是不会被打败的
I cannot be beaten.
我能看到他的思想
I see his mind,
我清楚他的每一个意图
I see his every intent.
没错
Yes.
我看到他转动光剑击中敌害
I see him turning the lightsaber to strike true.
而现在
And now,
傻孩子
foolish child,
他会点燃它
he ignites it,
杀死他真正的敌人
and kills his true enemy!
快 推进器全开 全速前进
Come on, give it full thrusters. Full speed!
已经开了 先生
I am, sir.
你这是谋杀 混蛋
You murdering bastard!
放轻松 大芬
T-T-Take it easy, Big F.
冤冤相报何时了
They blow you up today, you blow them up tomorrow.
不过是交易而已
It's just business.
你错了
You're wrong.
也许吧
Maybe.
本
Ben!
舰队
The fleet.
快命令他们停止开火
Order them to stop firing.
还有时间救舰队
There's still time to save the fleet.
本
Ben?
旧秩序该灭亡了
It's time to let old things die.
斯诺克
Snoke,
天行者
Skywalker.
西斯
The Sith,
绝地武士团 还有叛军
the Jedi, the Rebels…
都消失吧
Let it all die.
蕾伊
Rey.
请你加入我
I want you to join me.
我们一起 建立新秩序 统治银河系
We can rule together and bring a new order to the galaxy.
别这样 本
Don't do this, Ben.
不要走入歧途
Please don't go this way.
不 不 你还在坚持 放手吧
No, no. You're still holding on! Let go!
你想知道你父母的真相吗
Do you wanna know the truth about your parents?
又或者你一直都知道
Or have you always known?
只是在逃避而已
And you've just hidden it away.
你知道真相
You know the truth.
说出来
Say it.
说吧
他们谁也不是
They were nobody.
他们只是捡破烂的
They were filthy junk traders.
把你卖了 来换酒钱
who sold you off for drinking money.
最终死在贾库的一个贫民墓地
They're dead in a paupers' grave in the Jakku desert.
你在这个故事里毫无容身之所
You have no place in this story.
你毫无背景 你什么都不是
You come from nothing. You're nothing.
但你对我不一样
But not to me.
加入我
Join me.
拜托
Please.
长官
Sir,
抵抗军主舰要超空间跳跃了
the Resistance cruiser's preparing to jump to lightspeed.
毫无意义
It's empty.
他们只是想转移我们的注意力
They're just trying to pull our attention away.
可悲
Pathetic.
继续对运输机开火
Keep your fire on the transports.
枪毙便宜他们了
Execution by blaster is too good for them.
让他们尝点苦头
Let's make this hurt.
芬恩
Finn.
准备
On my command.
她跑了
She's running away.
不 她没有
No, she isn't.
- 不 - 快向那艘巡洋舰开火
- No! - Fire on that cruiser!
执行
Execute.
芬恩
Finn!
那边有一架飞船 快走
There's a shuttle back that way! We gotta go!
叛徒
Traitor!
怎么回事
What?
芬恩
Finn!
你就是军队的败笔
You are a bug in the system.
有种就来啊 铁光头
Let's go, chrome dome.
来啊
Come on!
不
No!
这边
Hey.
你一直都是渣滓
You were always scum.
叛军渣滓
Rebel scum.
喂 要搭便车吗
Hey! Need a lift?
到底发生了什么
What happened?
那个女孩谋杀了斯诺克
The girl murdered Snoke.
然后呢
What happened?
她坐上斯诺克的太空船跑了
She took Snoke's escape craft.
我们知道她的去向
We know where she's going.
集合所有的军队去抵抗军基地
Get all our forces down to that Resistance base.
做个了断吧
Let's finish this.
做了断
Finish this?
你以为你在命令谁
Who do you think you're talking to?
你认为你可以指挥我的军队吗
You presume to command my army?
最高领袖已经死了 我们不再有统治者了
Our Supreme Leader is dead! We have no ruler!
你的最高领袖已死
The Supreme Leader is dead.
最高领袖 万岁
Long live the Supreme Leader.
他们来了 关闭大门
They're coming, shut the door.
即将到来
Incoming!
快 快
Go! Go! Move!
快关闭盾门
Get that shield door down!
等等 不要开枪 是我们
No! Wait, don't shoot! It's us!
别开枪
No! Don't shoot!
先别开枪
Hold your fire!
- 别开枪 - 停火
- Don't shoot! - Hold your fire!
芬恩
Finn? Finn!
罗丝 你们还活着
Rose! You're not dead!
我的机器人呢
Where's my droid?
小伙伴
Buddy!
能见到你实在是太好了
I'm so glad to see you!
你说什么 等等 慢点说
Wait, what? Wait, wait, wait, slow down.
只剩下这些人了吗
Is this all that's left?
好了 护罩已开启 他们在外太空伤害不了我们
All right, shields are up so they can't hit us from orbit.
用我们手里的一切能源
Use whatever power we've got left.
向外环发送求救信号
to broadcast a distress signal to the Outer Rim.
用我的私人电码
Use my personal code.
如果抵抗军还有同盟的话
If there are any allies to the Resistance,
是时候来了
it's now or never.
罗丝 武器都有哪些
Rose, what do you got?
腐烂的弹药 生锈的大炮
Rotting munitions, rusted artillery,
摇摇晃晃的飞行艇
some half-gutted skim speeders.
好吧
Well,
只能祈祷那扇大门
let's just pray that big-ass door.
能够坚持到救援的到来
holds long enough for us to get help.
破城锤大炮
A battering ram cannon.
什么炮
A what now?
迷你版的死星技术
Miniaturized Death Star tech.
它能像小鸡破壳一样 炸开大门
It'll crack that door open like an egg.
这里一定有出路吧
There has to be a back way out of here, right?
BB-8 你有找到什么吗
BB-8, what do you got?
BB-8 分析了这座地矿的地图
BB-8 has analyzed the mine's schematics.
大门是唯一的进出口
This is the only way in or out.
振作起来
Come on.
我们还有同盟
We have allies.
盟友信任莱娅
People believe in Leia.
他们收到信号后 一定会来的
They'll get our message, they'll come.
现在我们要争取时间
But we have to buy time.
我们必须摧毁那些大炮
We gotta take out that cannon.
跟我来
On me! On me!
动起来
Move! Move!
回去收集武器
Go back! Gather your weapons!
过来这边
Get over here!
不要开火
Hold your fire!
是盐
Salt.
地面部队 敌方有动静
Ground forces, incoming.
收到 我们马上到
Copy that. On our way.
启动你的雪橇
Engage your mono-ski.
绿色的开关
The green toggle.
好了 大家都听着
All right, listen up.
这些生锈的废铁不好用 我们的胜算也很低 但是
I don't like these rust buckets and I don't like our odds, but…
什么情况
What the hell?
先保持队形
Just keep it tight.
在大炮开启之前
and don't get drawn in too.
不要飞得太靠近敌方
close till they roll that cannon out front.
地面部队 向敌方开火
All right, ground forces, lay down some fire!
十三架轻型飞行艇
Thirteen incoming light craft.
我们要不要先解决他们
Shall we hold until we clear them?
不用 抵抗军就在那地矿中
No. The Resistance is in that mine.
向前推进
Push through.
战斗机 散开
Fighters, break off!
坚持住 我们得拖住他们发射大炮
Come on! We gotta hold them till they pull up that cannon!
罗丝 你的后方有三个敌人
Rose, you got three right behind you!
我甩不掉他们
I can't lose 'em!
太棒了
Whoo! Yeah!
我喜欢
I like this!
把那垃圾飞船 给我从天上炸下来
Blow that piece of junk out of the sky!
所有战斗机
All fighters!
邱伊 快离开这儿
Chewie, peel off from the battle.
转移他们的注意力
Draw them away from the speeders.
她把所有的战斗机都带跑了
She drew 'em off! All of 'em!
他们可恨那艘飞船了
Oh, they hate that ship!
邱伊
Chewie!
就在那里
There it is!
这炮真是巨大
That is a big gun.
它的装甲非常厚重
Okay, it's heavily armored.
直击炮口是唯一的方法
Our only shot is right down the throat.
大炮要开启了 我们的机会来了
The cannon's opening. This is our chance.
火力集中在那些飞行艇上
All firepower on those speeders.
集中射击飞行艇
Concentrate all fire on the speeders!
我们损失惨重
We're taking heavy losses.
他们正在逐个击毁击毁我们 我们没有机会
They're picking us all off. We're not gonna make it.
最后一波进攻
All right, making my final approach.
目标已瞄准 枪支准备发射
Target in sight, guns are hot.
不行 撤退
No! Pull off!
什么
What?
大炮已经启动了 你这么做是自杀
The cannon is charged! It's a suicide run!
所有飞行艇 撤退
All craft, pull away!
- 不 我马上就要到了 - 快撤退 芬恩
- No! I'm almost there! - Retreat, Finn!
这是命令
That's an order!
芬恩 太迟了 不要这么做
Finn? It's too late! Don't do this!
不行 我不会让他们赢
No! I won't let them win!
不 芬恩 听波的命令
No! Finn, listen to Poe!
我们必须撤退
We have to retreat!
大炮正在预热期
The cannon is warming up now.
收到 我们看到了
Copy that. We see it.
准备攻击了
Preparing to fire.
快跑 快点逃离
Move! Go, go! Quick!
快跑 快跑
Let's go, let's go!
罗丝
Rose?
你为什么要那么做呢
Why would you do that? Huh?
我差一点就要成功了
I was almost there.
你为何要阻止我呢
Why would you stop me?
我救了你
I saved you,
傻瓜
dummy.
这样我们才能够胜利
That's how we're gonna win.
不是抵抗我们所恨
Not fighting what we hate,
而是拯救我们所爱
saving what we love.
赫克斯舰长
General Hux,
前进
advance.
斩草除根
No quarter.
不留俘虏
No prisoners.
我们的求救信号已被多方接收
Our distress signal's been received at multiple points,
但是没有任何回复
but no response.
他们听到了我们的呼救
They've heard us,
却不愿伸出援手
but no one's coming.
我们战斗到了最后
We fought till the end.
但是银河系 已失去了希望
But the galaxy has lost all its hope.
星星之火
The spark.
已然熄灭
is out.
卢克
Luke.
我知道你准备说什么
I know what you're gonna say.
我换了发型
I changed my hair.
这样也很好
It's nice that way.
莱娅
Leia,
对不起
I'm sorry.
我明白
I know.
我知道你很愧疚
I know you are.
你能够回来我已经很满足
I'm just glad you're here.
在最后
at the end.
我是来面对他的 莱娅
I came to face him, Leia.
我无力拯救他
And I can't save him.
一直以来 我都怀着希望
I held out hope for so long,
但我明白我的儿子已经消失了
but I know my son is gone.
没有人会真正的消失
No one's ever really gone.
卢克大师
Master Luke.
停
Stop!
给我把所有枪支对准那个人
I want every gun we have to fire on that man.
快点
Do it.
继续
More!
已经足够了
That's enough.
快停下来
That's enough!
你觉得你伤到他了吗
Do you think you got him?
好了 如果现在继续前进
Now, if we're ready to get moving,
我们就能了断这一切
we can finish this.
长官
Sir?
把我放下去
Bring me down to him.
把门关紧 没我的命令不准前进
Keep the door covered and don't advance until I say.
最高领袖
Supreme Leader,
请不要分心 我们的目标
don't get distracted, our goal…
收到 长官
Right away, sir.
急救队
Med pack!
我需要急救队
I need a med pack!
她伤得很严重
She's hurt pretty bad.
是凯洛·伦
It's Kylo Ren.
卢克独自一人面对他
Luke's facing him alone.
那我们应该去支援 走吧
Well, we should help him. Let's go.
不 等等
No, wait. Wait.
你是来告诉我 你原谅我了吗
Did you come back to say you forgive me?
你要拯救我的灵魂吗
To save my soul?
不是
No.
他这样做是别有用心
He's doing this for a reason.
他在为我们争取逃离时间
He's stalling so we can escape.
逃离
Escape?
他单枪匹马对抗一支军队
He's one man against an army.
我们要帮助他 继续战斗
We have to help him, we have to fight.
不 我们是燎原的星星之火
No, no. We are the spark that'll light the fire.
是烧毁第一秩序的大火
that'll burn the First Order down.
天行者这么做 是要保存火种
Skywalker's doing this so we can survive.
这个地矿一定有其他的出路
There's gotta be a way out of this mine.
不然他是怎么进来的
Hell, how did he get in here?
先生 确实可能存在一条未被发现的出路
Sir, it is possible that a natural unmapped opening exists.
但这里是一座迷宫 拥有无数条路
But this facility is such a maze of endless tunnels.
能够找到出口的概率
that the odds of finding an exit.
- 是一万五千四百二十八 - 嘘 别说话
- are 15, 428… - Shh. Shush. Hush. Shush up.
闭嘴
Shut up!
- 分之一 - 听
- To one. - Listen.
我的音频感受器 已经察觉不到…
My audio sensors no longer detect the…
正是如此
Exactly.
水晶狐都跑去哪里了
Where'd the crystal critters go?
跟我走
Follow me.
你们都看着我做什么
What are you looking at me for?
跟他走啊
Follow him.
如果信标在下方 他们一定就在附近
If the beacon's right beneath us, they've got to be somewhere.
继续扫描
Keep scanning for life forms.
这边
This way.
我看到他们了 邱伊 在那里
I see them! Chewie, there!
不 不 不 不
No. No, no, no.
不
No!
搬走石头
Lifting rocks.
我辜负了你 本
I failed you, Ben.
- 对不起 - 你当然对不起我
- I'm sorry. - I'm sure you are!
抵抗军已被消灭
The Resistance is dead.
战争结束了
The war is over.
等我杀了你
And when I kill you,
我就杀死了最后的绝地武士
I will have killed the last Jedi.
真是有趣
Amazing.
刚刚你所说的每一句话 都是错误的
Every word of what you just said was wrong.
起义军在今日得到了重生
The Rebellion is reborn today.
这场战争
The war.
才刚刚开始
is just beginning.
我也不会是最后的绝地武士
And I will not be the last Jedi.
我会毁灭她
I'll destroy her,
还有你
and you,
毁灭这一切
and all of it.
不
No.
即便你愤怒地向我挥刀 我也会一直在你身边
Strike me down in anger and I'll always be with you.
你的父亲也是如此
Just like your father.
不
No.
后会有期 孩子
See you around, kid.
不
No!
凯
C'ai!
好朋友
Such a friend.
邱伊
Chewie!
看起来很好
It looks good.
实在是疯狂
That was crazy, man.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
我是波
I'm Poe.
蕾伊
Rey.
我知道
I know.
等我们抵达外环 我有熟人在那里
When we get to the Outer Rim, I have a contact there.
这很有可能
Quite definitely possible.
卢克走了
Luke is gone.
我感觉到了
I felt it.
但他没有丝毫悲伤或痛苦
But it wasn't sadness or pain.
只有平静和决心
It was peace and purpose.
我也感受到了
I felt it, too.
我们现在该如何重建起义军呢
How do we build a Rebellion from this?
我们已经万事俱备了
We have everything we need.
卢克·天行者
Luke Skywalker,
绝地大师
Jedi Master.